Natalie Ortiz

p: (210) 744-2384 | e: ndnatalie@gmail.com | Github: natalieortiz | LinkedIn: ndnatalie | ndnatalie.com

SUMMARY

Web development project manager seeking a role in IT operations to include project management, SDLC support, testing, and coordination with cross-functional teams. Equipped with 5+ years experience in operational and project support roles to contribute to a productive, project-focused team environment. Currently working on a website for a local medicare agent and volunteering in the community.

TECHNICAL TOOLBOX

HTML | CSS | Twitter Bootstrap | JavaScript | jQuery | MySQL | PHP | Laravel | Git & Github | DNS

EDUCATION

Codeup, San Antonio, TX – 2016

Completed 16-week project-based immersion program in full-stack technologies to accelerate web development skills. Spent 480+ hours studying modern web technologies and building real projects.

University of Notre Dame, Notre Dame, IN – 2003

Obtained Bachelor of Business Administration in Management Information Systems. Manager of the Notre Dame Fighting Irish Football Team.

WEB DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

<u>Weather Finder</u> – Utilized JavaScript, jQuery, Google Maps API to allow a user to find a location using an in-browser map or search bar. Google Maps then geocodes data into coordinates and provides user with a 3-day weather forecast. <u>Link</u>: http://ndnatalie.com/weathermap

<u>Whack-a-weenie</u> – Developed custom whack-a-mole game using JavaScript and jQuery. The user has 30 seconds to hit as many dogs as possible. Used Twitter Bootstrap to integrate a modal response with an embedded YouTube video when user achieves a high score. <u>Link</u>: <u>http://ndnatalie.com/whackaweenie</u>

<u>Ad-lister Project</u> – Led 3-person team to create a Craigslist clone in PHP and HTML. Primarily responsible for the back-end functionality of the website utilizing homegrown framework. Used MySQL to generate and maintain the databases and PHP to provide the logic for the user to display, edit, and create ads. *Link*: http://peddlerscorner.ndnatalie.com/home

WEB DEVELOPMENT EXPERIENCE

<u>Giles-Parscale</u> - San Antonio, TX - *Assistant Development Manager*, July 2016 - November 2016 Assist in managing the development operations department for a design and web development agency. Duties include:

- Overseeing testing and finishing stages of web development project life cycle.
- Translate client website requirements into software development tasks and assign to developers accordingly.
- Prioritize, plan and track project progress to deliver projects on time and on budget.
- Add and update web content for client sites on WordPress and Expression Engine CMS platforms utilizing HTML, Javascript, and CSS.
- Perform go-live protocols by configuring servers, databases, and DNS to launch new websites.

ADDITIONAL OPERATIONAL EXPERIENCE

Project Management

- Worked with Human Resources and hiring managers to develop a relocation program for Rackspace to relocate 50+ new employees in 6 months.
- Provided coordination and project support to any large scale Product Management projects like SKU rationalization or new product roll-outs for Ventev Wireless Infrastructure.

Product Management

- Managed and tracked inventory forecasts as requested by Product Management.
- Set up SKUs and modified SKU attributes through Data Management Database.

Sales / Marketing Operations

- Served as content administrator for company website. Added and removed products and specification sheets and made changes to existing products on the website through content management software.
- Produced and delivered weekly sales and marketing reports to track market objectives.

WORK HISTORY

Ventev Wireless Infrastructure- San Antonio, TX - Sales Support Representative, 2014 - 2016

Peddle.com - Austin, TX- Loyalty Agent, 2012 - 2013

Apple, Inc. - Austin, TX- Mac Expert, 2011 - 2012

Clear - San Antonio, TX- Market Support Representative, 2009 - 2010

Museo Alameda - San Antonio, TX - Development Coordinator, 2008 - 2009

Rackspace - San Antonio, TX- Project Coordinator, Recruiting Coordinator, 2005 - 2008